http://www.bsac.com/this-is-bsac/bsac-rules-and-policies/privacy-policy/

Privacy notice
This site makes use of cookies. If you
continue we'll assume you are happy to receive them.
Menu
Rejoin BSAC todayInstructorsNews & blogQualification CardsMembershipBook training eventsShopLogin to MyBSAC
Training
Learn to scuba dive
Try scuba divingDiscovery Diver courseOcean Diver courseAccessibility - diving for allMore...
Online learning hub
BSAC eLearningProgramme of webinarsDiving skills to practice at home - videosUK wreck guides - videosMore...
Learn to snorkel
Try snorkellingFind a snorkel clubWhat gear will I need?Beginner coursesMore...
Skill Development Courses
Club diving coursesSafety and rescue coursesSeamanship coursesSpecial interest coursesMore...
More...
BSAC club life
Is club life for me?Get inspired by club life videosWhy choose BSAC?
Find a club or centre
Find a dive clubFind a centreFind a snorkelling clubFind a tech club
Try scuba diving with a club
Start a BSAC club
Support for new clubs
Already a qualified diver?
PADI, SAA or SSI Scuba Instructor?
Learn to dive
New to scuba diving?
Become a scuba diverWhy learn with BSAC?
Try scuba diving in a pool
Ocean Diver beginner course
How much will learning to dive cost? How long does it take to learn?What equipment will I need?
Learn to snorkel
More...
Already a diver
Qualified PADI (or other agency) diver?
Refresh your scuba skills
Start a diving club
Equivalent BSAC qualifications
More...
Learnt to scuba dive overseas?
Qualified PADI, SAA or SSI Instructor?
Why choose BSAC?
Other agency tech diver?
Snorkelling in the UK
More...
Diving and Snorkelling Incidents
In the event of a diving incidentReporting a diving incidentWhen you should report a diving incidentWhy you should report a diving incidentMore...
Member insurance
Summary of cover documentFull insurance policy wording
Medical matters and medical forms
Diving fitness and medical formsSnorkelling fitness and medical formsDownload medical referee formUKDMC medical conditionsMore...
DCI helpline - National Decompression Illness helpline
Oxygen administration trainingCasualty Assessment form
More...
Covid-19 advice and support
Official Covid-19-related statements and guidanceCovid-19 Safe Diving guidanceClub support during Covid-19Member support during Covid-19
Support for clubs
Club support during Covid-19Diving supportSnorkelling supportGrow your clubMore...
Support for instructors
Download instructor materialsOnline learning support for instructors in clubsInstructor exam supportDTP courses you can teachMore...
Support for centres
Diver training supportBSAC eLearning - how it all worksCentre instructor workshopsQCard Applications for CentresMore...
More...
What we do
TrainingClub lifeBSAC CentresBritish Sub-Aqua Jubilee TrustMore...
BSAC team
Volunteer vacanciesPresidentBSAC CouncilNational Diving CommitteeMore...
Governance
Get into governanceStrategic plan to 2020Minutes and reportsStrategic plan 2021-2023
Our history
Key milestonesBSAC pioneersArchive videos
BSAC rules and policies
GDPRChild safeguarding policyAdult safeguarding policyPrivacy policyMore...
Search
Join now
Privacy notice
You are here:This is BSACBSAC rules and policiesPrivacy notice
Share this page
What personal information do we hold?
Personal and contact details such as title, full name, contact details and address.
Your date of birth and gender.
Family members (if joint or family membership applies).
Photograph
How is personal information collected?
Personal information may be collected with the consent of the user by way of interactive submission or indirect submission via a BSAC branch.
How does BSAC use this information?
There are various reasons why personal information is gathered electronically which includes but is not limited to;
Provision of electronic services that require a user’s authenticity to be established.
Provision of other services offered by BSAC.
Participation in electronic surveys
Participation in events offered by BSAC
Information gathered with the explicit consent of the user will only be used for the purpose for which it was intended except in those circumstances where BSAC must provide it to fulfil statutory obligations. BSAC may use personal details to contact users directly for the purposes of obtaining further information needed to fulfil the original purpose.
BSAC may use personal information to contact users by electronic or physical means including but not limited to;
Sending e-mail to those that have requested it
Telephoning users to obtain additional information and clarification
Other electronic and physical correspondence.
Information that is gathered automatically without the explicit consent of the user will not be used by BSAC to identify an individual. BSAC may use this information for the purposes of demographic and statistical reporting with the purpose of enhancing the services that it offers to BSAC members and other users. BSAC may make this information available to others to fulfil its statutory obligations.
What is the legal basis for processing your personal information?
We rely on the following legal bases to use your personal data:
Where it is needed to provide you with our services to you as a member, such as:
Processing an application for a membership subscription you hold with us, including the price, the payment methods available and the conditions to attach.
Managing your subscription with us, or an application for one.
Updating your records to keep you up to date with your subscription and contact you regarding renewal.
Where it is in our legitimate interests to do so, such as:
Updating your records to keep you up to date with your subscription and contact you regarding renewal.
To perform and/or test the performance of our service to members and internal processes
For management and audit of our business operations including accounting
To carry out monitoring and to keep records of our communications with you and our staff
To administer our good governance requirements such as internal reporting and compliance obligations or administration required for AGM processes and elections to council.
For market research and analysis and developing statistics
To comply with our legal obligations.
How long is your personal information retained by us?
Unless we explain otherwise to you, we’ll hold your personal information based on the following criteria:
For as long as we have reasonable needs, such as managing our relationship with you and managing our service to you as a member
For as long as we provide services to you as a member
Retention periods in line with legal and regulatory requirements or guidance.
What should you do if your personal information changes?
You should tell us so that we can update our records using the details in the Contact Us section of our website. We’ll then update your records if we can.  Alternatively, you can update your details online in the MyBSAC section of our website.
Do you have to provide your personal information to us?
We’re unable to provide you with our services to you as a member if you do not provide certain information to us. In cases where providing some personal information is optional, we’ll make this clear.
What are your rights under data protection laws?
Here is a list of the rights that all individuals have under data protection laws. They don’t apply in all circumstances. If you wish to use any of them, we’ll explain at that time if they are engaged or not. The right of data portability is only relevant from May 2018.
The right to be informed about the processing of your personal information
The right to have your personal information corrected if it is inaccurate and to have incomplete personal information completed
The right to object to processing of your personal information
The right to restrict processing of your personal information
The right to have your personal information erased (the “right to be forgotten”)
The right to request access to your personal information and to obtain information about how we process it
The right to move, copy or transfer your personal information (“data portability”)
Rights in relation to automated decision making which has a legal effect or otherwise significantly affects you
BSAC reserves the right to charge an administration fee when a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if it is repetitive.  BSAC may also charge an administration fee to comply with requests for further copies of the same information.
The BSAC Data Protection Notification (registration Z8893394) may be viewed by visiting the Data Information Commissioners website.
You have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office which enforces data protection laws: https://ico.org.uk/. You can contact us at dpo@bsac.com.
Your right to object
You have the right to object to certain purposes for processing, in particular to data processed for direct marketing purposes and to data processed for certain reasons based on our legitimate interests. You can contact us by going to the Contact Us section of our website to exercise these rights.
What are your marketing preferences and what do they mean?
We may use your home address, phone numbers, email address and social media or digital channels (for example, Facebook, Google and message facilities in other platforms) to contact you according to your marketing preferences. You can stop our marketing at any time by contacting us at info@bsac.com or by following the instructions in the communication.
Security
BSAC will take reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal data it gathers in the course of operating electronic computer systems will be kept securely and within the control of BSAC at all times. BSAC will take reasonable precautions to ensure that all representations made for and on behalf of BSAC will be clearly identifiable.
Cookies
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue without changing your settings, we will assume that you are happy to receive all cookies on our website. However, if you would like to, you can change your cookie settings at any time.
Changes to this privacy notice
We may change this privacy notice from time to time by updating this page in order to reflect changes in the law and/or our privacy practices. We encourage you to check this privacy notice for changes whenever you revisit our website.
The current policy can also be obtained on request by emailing BSAC.
Contact us
If you have any questions or comments about this privacy notice, or if you wish to exercise your rights or contact the Data Protection Officer, you can contact us at dpo@bsac.com.
Share this page
BSAC rules and policies
GDPR
Child safeguarding policy
Adult safeguarding policy
Privacy policy
Acceptable usage policy
Website disclaimer
Find a club or centreLearn to diveRejoin BSAC todayContact usMedia centreBSAC rules and policiesSafeguardingPrivacy policyWebsite disclaimer
SitemapMembershipBook training eventsNeed help accessing MyBSAC?Medical matters and medical formsMember insurance
© 2020 British Sub-Aqua Club. Registered in England & Wales 01417376.
Website by NetXtra
